canon.ca 2018-10-24

# Privacy Policy | Canon Canada Inc.

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully, as it constitutes a binding agreement between you and Canon. By providing Personal Information to Canon or using the Online Services (as defined below), you acknowledge and signify that you have read, understood and agreed to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy.

Canon Canada Inc. together with its subsidiaries (“ **Canon** ”, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ” or “ **our** ”) is a market leader in business and consumer imaging equipment and information systems. Canon is committed to protecting the privacy of its customers' and potential customers’ Personal Information.

**1\. APPLICATION**

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, “Personal Information” means information that can identify an individual, provided that Personal Information does not include the name, title, business address or business telephone number of an employee of an organization when such information is used for the purposes consistent with the person’s employment position, and Personal Information shall be interpreted in a manner that conforms with the requirements of applicable provincial and federal privacy legislation.

This Privacy Policy applies to Personal Information:

(i) we may collect in any form completed by individuals including our customers, potential customers and visitors looking to purchase or inquiring about Canon products; (ii) obtained from www.canon.ca and other Canon owned and operated websites or Canon mobile applications that link to this Privacy Policy (such websites and applications referred to as the “ **Online Services** ”); and (iii) “user generated content” or “UGC” meaning any form of content such as blogs, wikis, discussion forums, posts, chats, tweets, podcasting, pins, digital images, video, audio files, and other forms of media that was created by users as part of the Online Services or otherwise.

This Privacy Policy does not apply, however, to Canon’s employees in the context of their employment with Canon. There is a separate policy to address the protection of Canon’s employees’ (and potential employees’) privacy in the context of their employment relationship with Canon.

If you are a Canon employee or have submitted an application for employment with Canon and wish to see the privacy policy applicable to your information, please request a copy of that privacy policy.

**2\. AGE OF MAJORITY**

Canon requests that only persons who have reached the age of majority or legal age in their jurisdiction and who can form legally binding contracts under applicable law provide Personal Information to us. If you are providing Personal Information to Canon on your own behalf, you hereby represent and warrant that you have reached the age of majority in your jurisdiction and you otherwise have the legal capacity to agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.  **If you provide Personal Information on anyone under the age of 18, you must be the person’s parent or legal guardian and have the right to provide the Personal Information under all applicable laws.**  You are fully responsible for ensuring that the Personal Information of persons under the age of 18 that you provide can be collected, used, stored and disclosed by Canon as described in this Privacy Policy.

**3\. ACCOUNTABILITY**

Canon is accountable for all Personal Information under its care and control. Canon's Privacy Officer is designated as the person responsible for this Privacy Policy and for the Personal Information received by Canon, and for ensuring its compliance with applicable privacy legislation. Any questions relating to Canon's handling of Personal Information or this Privacy Policy should be directed to our Privacy Officer. The Privacy Officer can be reached by e-mail at [privacy@canada.canon.com](mailto:privacy@canada.canon.com).

Canon has implemented policies and practices to give effect to this Privacy Policy, including:

\- procedures governing the collection, storage, use, disclosure, protection and accuracy of Personal Information;  
\- procedures that analyze new initiatives which may affect Personal Information;  
\- procedures to receive and respond to inquiries and complaints; and  
\- internal staff training about Canon’s policies and practices.  

**4\. TYPES OF INFORMATION COLLECTED AND THE PURPOSES**

The type of information that you may provide Canon or that Canon may collect is tied to the purposes for which the information is collected. Often, it is tied to the products or services you request, or to the nature of the interaction between you and Canon. A few more typical examples of this are set out below.

If you decide to contact Canon to ask a question, learn more about a product or register a recently purchased product, download certain software or service applications, place an order for products or inquire about products you may already own, you will find that those contact forms ask for certain types of Personal Information to assist us in complying with these requests. Canon may also ask you to provide Personal Information, some optional, some required, on specific pages of our websites or through the Online Services. The type of Personal Information we ask for in these situations can include (but is not limited to) name, mailing address, email address, phone number, shipping information, product model and serial numbers and your dates of purchase, credit card, debit card or other payment account information and your comments. Personal Information may be forwarded to a Canon business unit or the appropriate Canon affiliate that is equipped to handle your order, inquiry or feedback.

As noted, when using the Online Services, sometime the provision of Personal Information is optional and sometimes it is required. It may be necessary to provide Personal Information in order to access certain features offered through the Online Services. If you do not wish provide any Personal Information, you can choose not to use those features of the Online Services.

We may also retain any UGC and messages you send through the Online Services, and may collect information you provide in UGC you create, share, or post to the Online Services, which may include information contained in your profile as well as photos or other image files and associated metadata. By its nature, UGC is often shared as part of a social media experience. This means that UGC is publicly available. UGC may not necessarily reflect the views of Canon.

Personal Information is also collected by means of warranty cards, trade show information, e-mail, voluntary online surveys and as part of any entry for a contest or other promotion. If you choose to enter a contest or other promotion we conduct, you will be required to submit certain Personal Information, such as your name, e-mail address, street address and phone number. We will use the required Personal Information you submit to us for promotion administration purposes, such as notification of winners.

In the course of growing or restructuring our business, we may also purchase the assets of another company or sell the assets of our company. During these transactions, information about customers is frequently considered a business asset that is the subject of such a purchase or sale.

We may collect metadata associated with the use of the Online Services. Metadata is data that serves to provide context or additional information about other data. Metadata is often called data about data or information about information. For example, information about the title, subject, author, typeface, enhancements, and size of the data file of a document constitute metadata about that document. It may also describe the conditions under which the data stored in a database was acquired, its accuracy, date, time, method of compilation and processing, etc.

When you access the Online Services through a mobile device, we may collect information on your device. This identifier is a critical tool that allows app developers, advertisers, analytic companies and others to identify a user’s device for purposes of storing application preferences, to better understand what’s working in the app and what problems needs to be fixed. It is also the only persistent means of tracking advertising and marketing activity on and across devices, because the app ecosystem does not generally support the use of cookies.

When you access the Online Services through a mobile device, we may collect information on your location. Location data is information collected by a network or service about where the user’s phone or other device is or was located. For example, location data would include tracing the location of a mobile phone from data collected by base stations on a mobile phone network.

Through the use of the Online Services, we may provide ads on our websites and apps, as well as on other companies' websites and apps. Some of the ads we may show you are based on the content of the page or app you are viewing. Other ads we show you may be based on information we have collected or received about your activities and interests.

 _Online Services User Information_

Canon routinely gathers information on website activities such as data on how many people visit a website, the pages they visit, where they come from, how long they stay, etc. Such information is gathered through the use of web server logs. A web server log is a file where website activity is stored.

User information is collected on an aggregate, anonymous basis, which means that no Personal Information is associated with this data.

 _Non-Personal Information_

Canon also collects information that, alone, cannot be used to identify you (referred to as " **non-Personal Information** ") through the Online Services. Examples of types of non-Personal Information that we may collect include gender, age, survey responses, IP addresses and data stored in cookie files. We describe some of these examples in more detail below:

(a) Internet Protocol Addresses: An Internet Protocol (IP) address is a number automatically assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. This number does not identify your name, e-mail address or other Personal Information. If you request information from a website, our server will enter your IP address into a server log, which may automatically collect and store information in relation to how you used our Online Services, any system activity or crashes, etc. We use this information to measure website traffic, to help us to understand how people are using our Online Services and to hopefully improve your online experience.

(b) Cookies: Our website may gather certain non-Personal Information through the use of "cookies." "Cookies" are small text files that recognize repeat visitors, facilitate ongoing access to some sites, and allow sites to understand how and when pages are visited and by how many people. Users who are concerned about the use of cookie technology may opt to enable a feature in their browser software that will erase cookies, block all cookies, or warn the user before cookies are stored or exchanged. Please be aware however, that some parts of our website may no longer function properly if cookies are disabled.

(c) Analytics: We may collect analytics data associated with the use of the Online Services. The term “analytics” refers to the use of information technology to harness statistics, algorithms, and other tools of mathematics to improve decision-making. Analytics provide a way for us to draw on the great quantities of information and to use the data to make better decisions and to create new products and services.

**5\. USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We use your Personal Information is a manner that is reasonably connected to the purposes for which it was collected. For example, we use your Personal Information for the following reasons:

\- to provide you with the services that you request.  
\- to respond to questions you may have about our products or services;  
\- We may use the Personal Information you provide about yourself when placing an order or registering for warranty or out of warranty service to complete that order or service registration and to provide you with information about other Canon products and promotions that may be of interest to you.  
\- User generated content is often part of a larger discussion of various topics and enhances the experience of other visitors to the Online Services or Canon Website in terms of seeing opinions, reviews or general discussions on various topics.  
\- We may use your information in aggregate form to help us evaluate and modify existing services, and to help us develop additional services that are likely to be of interest to our users.  **You can always choose not to be contacted or to "opt-out" on the registration screen on which your Personal Information is entered.**  If you later decide that you do not want your Personal Information used for these purposes, you may opt-out by sending an e-mail or letter to us. Please refer to Openness and Access below.  

**6\. CONSENT**

Canon obtains the consent of customers to the collection, use or disclosure of Personal Information by Canon where appropriate, except as permitted by law, or as required by law or a recognized authority. Sometimes an individual's consent may be implied through his or her conduct with Canon.

**By providing Personal Information to Canon, you are consenting to the terms and information handling practices set out in this Privacy Policy.**

Canon does not, as a condition of entering into a product or service agreement in connection with the Online Services, require a customer to consent to the collection, use or disclosure of Personal Information beyond that required in fulfilling the identified purposes.

Customers may withdraw their consent for any identified purpose at any time, subject to legal and/or contractual restrictions and reasonable notice. Customers may contact the Privacy Officer at [privacy@canada.canon.com](mailto:privacy@canada.canon.com) for more information regarding the implications of such withdrawal.

**7\. DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Rest assured, Canon will only provide Personal Information to third parties on an “as needed” basis and provided that such third parties have privacy policies in place. In addition, Canon uses contractual agreements or other means to provide a comparable level of protection with respect to Personal Information handled by Canon’s subsidiaries, affiliates, agents, contractors and authorized dealers. Below are a few examples of when and why Canon may share Personal Information.

Your Personal Information may be shared with our employees, independent contractors, agents or other entities that are related to Canon and/or business partners (collectively, “Service Providers”) acting on our behalf to: (i) fulfill and/or ship an order or provide a product or service you have requested; (ii) provide an award; (iii) provide mail-in or other rebate on the products that you may purchase; (iv) conduct customer surveys for the purpose of marketing; (v) apply for employment with Canon; and/or (vi) collect debt or other payments.

User generated content is typically part of a social media experience and will be publicly available. We ask that you keep that in mind when posting any user generated content.

Canon Operations and Maintenance Contractors: Canon may share your Personal Information with third-party contractors as is necessary to respond to your requests for products and information. Third-party contractors may access your Personal Information in order to send you information on behalf of Canon.

Canon also may hire third-party technology providers to host its websites and to store your Personal Information.

We may use your Personal Information and disclose your Personal Information to third parties in connection with the proposed or actual financing, insuring, sale, securitization, assignment or other disposal of all or part of Canon’s business or assets for the purposes of evaluating and/or performing the proposed transaction. Our successors and assigns may collect, use and disclose your Personal Information for substantially the same purposes as those set out in this Privacy Policy. In the event the transaction does not go through, Canon will require, by contract, the other party or parties to the transaction not to use or disclose your Personal Information in any manner whatsoever for any purpose, and to return or destroy such Personal Information. Also, in the unlikely event that Canon’s assets are acquired or subject to liquidation in bankruptcy, Personal Information may be transferred as well.

Except as otherwise set forth herein, or permitted or required by law, we do not share your Personal Information with any companies that are unrelated to Canon except to the extent necessary to complete the purposes set out herein or for purposes reasonably necessary to fulfill our obligations to you and, when we do share it, it is subject to their agreement to both treat it as confidential business information and to fully comply with all applicable privacy laws and also with the understanding that it may not be used for any purpose other than to perform their function.

**8\. LINKED SITES**

As a convenience to our visitors, the Online Services may contain links to a number of sites that we believe may offer useful information. When you click on one of these links, you will be transferred from the Online Services and be connected to the site of the organization or company that you selected.  ** _This Privacy Policy is no longer applicable when you are on a website that is not Canon’s, even if you get to that new website by way of link from Canon’s Online Services._**  Each of these linked sites maintains their own independent privacy policies and procedures, which you should consult before providing any of your Personal Information.

**9\. SECURITY**

Canon works hard to ensure that our systems are secure and that they meet industry standards. To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place the following physical, electronic, and organizational procedures to safeguard and secure the Personal Information we collect online:

\- physical measures such as locked filing cabinets and restricted access to offices;  
\- organizational measures such as staff training, security clearances and restrictions on employee access to Personal Information; and  
\- technological measures such as the use of passwords, encryption, firewalls, and anonymizing software.  
\- Canon Canada is PCI compliant. In order to ensure payments made online are as secure as reasonably possible, the Payment Card Industry (PCI) created a set of security standards designed to ensure that ALL companies that accept, process, store or transmit credit card information maintain a secure environment. Canon meets or exceeds these standards.  

Canon stores Personal Information in secure and confidential databases in its offices across Canada and/or the United States.

Canon also takes reasonable steps to protect Personal Information disclosed to:

\- subsidiaries and affiliates of Canon by ensuring that such entities institute appropriate controls on the use and disclosure of Personal Information; and  
\- agents, contractors and authorized dealers of Canon through the use of contractual agreements which limit the circumstances in which Personal Information may be used and disclosed. These agreements ensure that Personal Information is retained only as long as necessary to complete the assigned task.  

**10\. STORAGE OUTSIDE CANADA**

Your Personal Information may be used or stored by us or our Service Providers and our corporate affiliates outside of Canada, in the United States. Canon takes reasonable contractual or other measures to protect customer’s Personal Information while processed or handled by these Service Providers and our corporate affiliates outside of Canada. If a customer’s Personal Information is located outside of Canada it will be subject to legal requirements in those foreign countries applicable to Canon’s Service Providers and corporate affiliates. For example, information that is processed, used, stored or accessed in the United States may be subject to the Patriot Act and applicable anti-terrorism legislation, together with other legislation applicable within the United States.

**11\. UPDATING INFORMATION**

Canon makes every effort to keep Personal Information accurate, complete and current, however, Canon will not routinely update the Personal Information of customers, unless such a process is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the information was collected. It may be necessary for customers to supply Canon with written consent in order for Canon to collect and update Personal Information that is not necessary to fulfill the identified purposes. Canon will update any changes to Personal Information when received. If Canon holds Personal Information about an individual which can be established by the individual to be inaccurate, incomplete or not up-to-date, Canon will take reasonable steps to correct it.

**12\. OPENNESS AND ACCESS**

The following information is readily available to customers:

\- information that explains Canon's privacy policies;  
\- the name of the department holding the customer's Personal Information;  
\- access by email to Canon’s Privacy Officer;  
\- the means by which they may access their Personal Information; and  
\- a description of the type of Personal Information held by Canon, including a general account of its use.  

To the extent possible, customers may obtain information regarding the identity of the subsidiaries, affiliates, agents, contractors and authorized dealers of Canon to whom Canon has disclosed Personal Information and the purposes for which these third parties may use the information.

Canon provides customers with information about its privacy policies and practices through written materials, Canon's website and its interactive voice response system.

If you have any questions about Canon’s information handling practices, if you would like to access your Personal Information, or request that your Personal Information be modified, corrected or removed from our database, please contact Canon's Privacy Officer at [privacy@canada.canon.com](mailto:privacy@canada.canon.com).

Canon will make all reasonable efforts to respond within thirty (30) days of your request (the “ **Notice Period** ”). Canon may extend the Notice Period when

\- responding within the Notice Period would unreasonably interfere with the activities of Canon; or  
\- the time required to undertake any consultations necessary to respond to the request would make the Notice Period impractical to meet.  

To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. Canon will use reasonable efforts to supply you with this information and to correct any factual inaccuracies that you identify.

Canon will respond to requests for access to Personal Information at no cost for access or minimal cost for access. Where there is a cost for access to Personal Information, Canon will provide the individual with an estimate of the approximate cost. Upon receipt of the estimate, the individual must advise Canon if he or she wishes to continue with the request. The request will be put on hold until such time as Canon receives confirmation to proceed with the request based on approval of the fees involved.

Under certain conditions as permitted or required by law, Canon will not provide individuals with access to the Personal Information kept on file by Canon. Where Canon refuses a request from, Canon Canada will identify: (i) the reasons for refusing the request; and (ii) the recourse for the customer under applicable legislation.

**13\. CHANGES TO POLICY**

Canon reserves the right to modify, add or remove portions of this Privacy Policy at any time and from time to time, acting in its sole and unfettered discretion. If we decide to change this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on our website ([www.canon.ca](http://www.canon.ca/)) or send a notification via electronic communication, which will be effective within thirty (30) days after posting.

© Canon Canada Inc., 2017. All rights reserved. Reproduction in whole or in part without permission is prohibited.
